<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Precision Farming on Tania ・ Open Source Farm Management Sofware</title>
    <link>https://usetania.org/categories/precision-farming/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Precision Farming on Tania ・ Open Source Farm Management Sofware</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-gb</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Mon, 23 Sep 2019 17:23:09 +0800</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="https://usetania.org/categories/precision-farming/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Precision Farming: What You Need to Know in Advance and How to Make The Most of It</title>
      <link>https://usetania.org/blog/make-the-most-of-precision-farming/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 23 Sep 2019 17:23:09 +0800</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://usetania.org/blog/make-the-most-of-precision-farming/</guid>
      <description>You probably have heard the term precision farming or precision agriculture almost from everywhere. But how much do you understand it? Precision farming is a booming sector, involves various equipment and lengthy knowledge and resources to work. And some farmers can be a bit confused. Do you feel the same way too? Let&amp;rsquo;s break it down.
What is Precision Farming? It&amp;rsquo;s definitely more than just using a farm management system and do your daily work at your farm&amp;hellip;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Increasing Efficiency with Precision Farming; How Satellites Can Help Farmers</title>
      <link>https://usetania.org/blog/increasing-efficiency-with-precision-farming/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 18 Sep 2019 17:15:36 +0800</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://usetania.org/blog/increasing-efficiency-with-precision-farming/</guid>
      <description>Do you know that 37% of Earth&amp;rsquo;s land is used for agricultural purposes? 11% is used for growing crops, and the rest is for pastures. One of the most overlooked challenges in agriculture is maintaining and improving efficiency. With climate changes already happen everywhere, humanity will have to face and tackle these challenges. Why? As the population only continues to grow, much of the world will depend on more effective agriculture practices to produce more outputs the world population relies on.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>