<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>What is Tania? on Tania | Open Source Farm Management Sofware</title>
    <link>https://usetania.org/docs/</link>
    <description>Recent content in What is Tania? on Tania | Open Source Farm Management Sofware</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-gb</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Mon, 04 Feb 2019 18:14:30 +0800</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="https://usetania.org/docs/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Initial setup</title>
      <link>https://usetania.org/docs/initial-setup/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 05 Mar 2019 12:16:55 +0800</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://usetania.org/docs/initial-setup/</guid>
      <description>After you have finished the installation step of Tania, you can start using the software by accessing http://localhost:8080 (the default installation address.) Input tania as the default username and password.
On the next screen, you will input the information about your farm. Fill all fields and click Continue.
Next, you will define the source of water on your farm. You can choose the Tap/Well for the infinite water source, or you can choose Water tank/Cistern if you have the finite water source.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Settings</title>
      <link>https://usetania.org/docs/settings/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 04 Feb 2019 19:55:09 +0800</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://usetania.org/docs/settings/</guid>
      <description>You can change the default password from this section.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Inventory</title>
      <link>https://usetania.org/docs/inventory/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 04 Feb 2019 19:55:03 +0800</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://usetania.org/docs/inventory/</guid>
      <description>Before you can start using Tania to track your growing activities, you must register seeds that you have to the inventory section. In this section, you can also record your tools, fertilisers, and any other supplies.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Reservoir</title>
      <link>https://usetania.org/docs/reservoir/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 04 Feb 2019 19:54:57 +0800</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://usetania.org/docs/reservoir/</guid>
      <description>On the reservoir section, you can manage and create tasks that relate to the particular reservoir.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Crop</title>
      <link>https://usetania.org/docs/crop/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 04 Feb 2019 19:54:51 +0800</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://usetania.org/docs/crop/</guid>
      <description>Crop section is the heart of Tania. In this section, you can record and track activities regarding each crop you plant. Whenever you create a new growing crops batch, Tania will give it an identification string so you can trace that from seed to harvest/waste.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Area</title>
      <link>https://usetania.org/docs/area/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 04 Feb 2019 19:54:45 +0800</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://usetania.org/docs/area/</guid>
      <description>You can get all information about your crops, tasks, and record the watering activities for the particular area.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Dashboard</title>
      <link>https://usetania.org/docs/dashboard/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 04 Feb 2019 19:54:39 +0800</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://usetania.org/docs/dashboard/</guid>
      <description>There is 3 grouped information on the dashboard:
 At a glance is the number of areas on your farm, varieties that you plant, and tasks that you have. Crops is the current plant you are growing and the quantity of each batch. Tasks is the to-do list activity on your farm.  </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Getting Help</title>
      <link>https://usetania.org/docs/getting-help/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 04 Feb 2019 19:47:55 +0800</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://usetania.org/docs/getting-help/</guid>
      <description>Raising Issues Please raise any bug reports on Tania&amp;rsquo;s Github issue trackers. Be sure to search the list to see if your issue has already been raised.
A good bug report is one that make it easy to understand what you were trying to do and what went wrong.
Feature requests For feature requests, please raise and discuss them on Tania&amp;rsquo;s Telegram group.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Installation</title>
      <link>https://usetania.org/docs/installation/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 04 Feb 2019 19:34:29 +0800</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://usetania.org/docs/installation/</guid>
      <description>This software is built with Go programming language. It means you will get an executable binary to run on your machine. You don&amp;rsquo;t need extra software like MAMP, XAMPP, or WAMP to run Tania, but you may need MySQL database if you choose to use it instead of SQLite (the default database.)
The easiest way to install Tania is using pre-built binaries for Windows (x64) and Linux (x64). You can download it from the release page.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>